Daz: Hey, hey!
Ben Pfaff: Hello!
Joe Beda: Hello, hello.
Daz: Hello, hello. How is everyone doing?
Ben Pfaff: I'm doing well.
Daz: Desk is a bit of a mess, so my…
Joe Beda: Yeah, my office started out clean when we moved into this house, and it's slowly deteriorating, and I need to take another pass at it.
Ben Pfaff: I'm, beginning to remember why owning a house is a pain sometimes.
Joe Beda: This is my take, is that, like, it doesn't matter what house it is, it's like… you're like, oh, the new house will be better. No, you're just trading old problems for new problems, there is no, like…
Ben Pfaff: Well, the… the… Current problem is that the irrigation system stopped working in some of the zones.
Joe Beda: Well, you just need to get a shovel and fix it. I mean, like…
Ben Pfaff: Well, so there were people, like, dragging pipes by some of them a couple weeks ago, because the sewer lateral needed to be replaced, so I suspect that something got bumped, or screwed up, or whatever, and I don't know how any of it works, because I didn't put it in, so I'm gonna have to go find out.
Joe Beda: Yeah, that's the other thing with the house, there's always spelunking, right? Like…
Ben Pfaff: Well, there's actually a very nice map and list of what's supposed to be where, but… I mean, it doesn't help enough. It just… it just means that I know what those… what should… what those zones numbers should be.
Joe Beda: Well, like, the previous house, I moved in, and there was, like.
Joe Beda: Cat5 run to a bunch of places.
Joe Beda: but it was used as telephone wire, and so then it was put into sort of punchdown blocks that was telephone. Nothing was labeled in terms of which cable went where, and then all the jacks were RJ11 instead of RJ45, so, like…
Joe Beda: I had to get, like, a tone generator and go through and, like, map those things out, and then I had this handwritten list of, like, well… and then I got these new, like, punch-down, little punch-down things, and then I had a handwritten list of, like, well, you know, number one on this block is blah blah blah.
Joe Beda: And I left that for the new owner, I'm like, you can thank me later.
Ben Pfaff: Echo.
Daz: Awesome.
Joe Beda: Hey, how's it going, man?
Daz: Hey, Kostadis.
Kostadis Roussos: Putting on my headphones.
Joe Beda: Where are you at?
Joe Beda: You are in a hotel room.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll tell you in a second, give me a sec.
Joe Beda: That is definitely hotel room-esque.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Ben Pfaff: Did that help? Let's see.
Joe Beda: Looks like a nice hotel room, though.
Ben Pfaff: Nope.
Ben Pfaff: Well, thanks, Jane.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: They get the right devices.
Ben Pfaff: I'm saying you said a spider.
Ben Pfaff: Slider.
Ben Pfaff: It slides from side to side, not spider.
Joe Beda: Is Gabe joining us today, do you know?
Daz: No, he said he was out for the next 2 weeks, I think, last time.
Joe Beda: Wow, bummer.
Ben Pfaff: That's all.
Ben Pfaff: Jamie has a lot more space in this place, and I guess it's making her less excited about sitting and watching me play DnD.
Joe Beda: her Monday Entertainment anymore?
Ben Pfaff: I guess not.
Ben Pfaff: like, there's a… there's a TV here that isn't directly back of where I'm sitting.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so yes, I'm in a hotel room in LA. My son is doing an internship at a
Kostadis Roussos: At a company, I have a buddy of mine.
Joe Beda: And you're visiting and saying hi?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm taking care of him. He's 16 years old, I can't have him staying alone in the way.
Joe Beda: Oh, interesting.
Joe Beda: So… Nora's doing an internship, she's 17, but she's doing it remote because the company doesn't have any offices.
Kostadis Roussos: I see.
Joe Beda: So I have discussions with her, I'm like, you're playing guitar. They're paying you for this time. Are there things that you can be doing? She's like, well, I'm blocked on something and waiting for somebody to reply. I'm like, well, in the real world, you have multiple, you know, balls in the air that you juggle, and when you get blocked on one thing, you find something else to be useful for, and like…
Joe Beda: She did not appreciate my feedback, so, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Did I appreciate your feedback.
Joe Beda: No, it turns out that a lot of times the kids don't appreciate my sage advice. I don't understand it.
Ben Pfaff: Well, you know, I've got days where I just can't deal, and I spend some of my downtime doing things that aren't necessarily advancing stockholder value.
Joe Beda: Yeah, I mean, but you got, like, there's a balance there, and I just don't… I want her to be aware of, like, hey, like, you know, don't, like…
Joe Beda: Fall into the trap of, like, sooner or later, you know.
Joe Beda: over time, you spend more and more time goofing off, and it's… I mean, that's one of the dangers of working remote, right, is that it's easy to fall into that sort of goofing off trap.
Ben Pfaff: That is true.
Kostadis Roussos: Especially for junior engineers who don't have a good work ethic.
Joe Beda: They're still… I would say that.
Kostadis Roussos: We're still developing.
Joe Beda: developing their habits, is what I would say.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, actually, what I say is, when I… when I say… when I tell my new MTS1s, and they… for some reason, they don't let me speak to them anymore after I said this.
Ben Pfaff: All my bad habits are.
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly.
Ben Pfaff: grand, no.
Kostadis Roussos: I tell them, step zero, oh, step zero, you have to prove to me you know how to… you know how to work. They look at me funny, you know, like, show up to work every day.
Kostadis Roussos: Apparently, apparently that is considered poor form, and not the kind of things that is appropriate to be said to new hires.
Kostadis Roussos: So you're officially the.
Joe Beda: Grumpy old man Kostadis.
Kostadis Roussos: So, by consensus, I don't meet the MTS ones. I only meet them when they're MTS2s. That way they… that way… that way I don't terrify them.
Kostadis Roussos: That way there's… that way there's not meetings with HR and discussions and things like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so…
Joe Beda: Alright, we're just gonna play.
Kostadis Roussos: So… Or you want to shoot the shit? Gabe's out. Oh, no, we can play.
Ben Pfaff: So, I've been bad here, and I haven't done my homework on what we're doing.
Kostadis Roussos: You rat bastard. All right. Yeah. So, that's, you know, I figured as much, so I've prepared. I'm not even sure…
Ben Pfaff: How many sessions we've had in between?
Kostadis Roussos: 2.
Ben Pfaff: True.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I don't.
Joe Beda: I think I was at the last one, but I'm not sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so here's what happened. You guys all managed to secure… I mean, I have a summary if you want it, I can share it with you.
Ben Pfaff: I, I like hearing… I like hearing the words, if you're willing.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, no, I'm absolutely willing to do that. I'm just, like… the reason I said that was to give me a moment to go pull it up.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: It was more of a, hmm, give me a shot.
Kostadis Roussos: So, okay, so here's what happened.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, okay, so you secured Alcrist's confession. You had physical evidence, and then you started to debate your own…
Kostadis Roussos: at your own… you started to, you started to debate what to happen. Don Bringer, of course, at that point in time, decided this was an opportune time to discuss that the promises, therapy sessions, which scandal keeps calling, literally said, never materialize.
Kostadis Roussos: And, Thorin was very sympathetic and understanding and said, I know, this is why we came here after all.
Kostadis Roussos: Finally, after some deliberation, the group settled on a patient strategy, hand the credit to Callan Stormbranch, let him save face after his humiliating dismissal, and collect a reward.
Kostadis Roussos: You guys thought, with all the evidence you had, you'd be able to go in and march in and have… everybody would bow before you.
Kostadis Roussos: However, Callan pointed out that,
Kostadis Roussos: That to temper your expectations, he argued with academic precision that a single confession, however dramatic, was not enough to bring Bookworm to justice under the rigorous standards of his own investigative framework.
Kostadis Roussos: He shoved his paper, the thrice-fold proof, into their faces, and insisted that the clever play was patience.
Kostadis Roussos: With the naming ceremony approaching, the stench of suspicion alone would be enough to deny Bookworm the position of first keeper, and the new head of the avowed would be far more motivated to see her undone.
Kostadis Roussos: The party agreed, and then Thorin added a cunning wrinkle of his own. They would use the reward to acquire whatever resource or tome that might definitively prove Bookworm's role as an accomplished after the fact, striking when she least suspect it.
Kostadis Roussos: The confrontation in Bookworm's office was a master class in controlled tension. She received you with regal composure, pouring tea and gesturing for you to sit, an offer you declined with varying degrees of suspension. Zalter, unwilling to be rude, but equally unwilling to trust the cup, quietly directed Glavagold to absorb the three through his arm.
Kostadis Roussos: The faint cinch of acid, the only sign anything unusual had occurred.
Kostadis Roussos: When Colin laid out the evidence against Alcaris, the stolen poison, the book, the confession, the bookworm's composure cracked, and she appeared heartbroken. But Daz, watching her attack carefully, noticed something the others missed. Beneath the grief, she looked curiously relieved.
Kostadis Roussos: We chose to withhold what they knew about the potential accomplices, hinting only that the investigation was not yet complete, and that others may have been involved.
Kostadis Roussos: Bookworm performed outreach beautifully, declaring it unthinkable that anyone would have conspired in the death of her beloved Genusi.
Kostadis Roussos: Colin was reinstated to his position, his methodology vindicated at last, and Brightroom graciously announced that the party would be given a full opportunity to speak before the naming ceremony. She then arranged for them to be escorted to Denier Sagintom, framing it as protection.
Kostadis Roussos: Though Daz sensed it was equally about keeping them from poking their noses any further into Candlekeep's affairs. A brief detour to Alcist's room yielded little of consequence. The safe contained gold, a pair of potions, as a…
Kostadis Roussos: Joe put it, Jimmy Hoffa's, Jimmy Hoffa's, chest.
Kostadis Roussos: A gold coin with a red herring engraved upon it, a fitting symbol for an investigation full of misdirection. The avowed declared that the contents unremarkable and moved to close the matter, buts out there, never one to miss an opportunity, used Glavagul to quietly pocket the potion of flying while everyone else was distracted. No one knows a thing.
Kostadis Roussos: The piece shattered without warning. Okay, so the evening in Dinier Sanctum passed quietly at first. Food was brought in, which the party eyed with deep suspicion, allowing Fembrus to eat first before touching anything themselves.
Kostadis Roussos: Donbringer was finally called upon to cure Darrell of his lingering affliction, and the man was so overcome with gratitude that he launched an enthusiastic monologue about his plans to make sentient magical swords an area of serious academic study, going on a considerable length about the semiotics of the subject, while Sam Donbringer absorbed every word with evident delight.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl then attempted to leave the room, only to find it was Locke. The piece shattered without warning. Three helmed hormers, twowering animated suits of plate armor with cold, glowing eyes.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, that's a classic.
Kostadis Roussos: Smashed through the windows and burst through the door of the sanctum, sending the room into chaos. The construct moved with terrifying purpose, ignoring most of the party and converging almost entirely on Dads.
Kostadis Roussos: It was fully mid-battle, as the horrors relentlessly bypassed every other target to reach them, that Raz realized with a chill what they were after. The mysterious key carried, the one that had appeared completely inert to magical detection.
Kostadis Roussos: He passed it to Gregam, and threw himself clear as his companion surged into the fight.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, the battle is fierce and disoriented. Saltir drove his fists into the animated armor, while Glabagul, fused to his arm, unleashed torrents of corrosive acid that began dissolving the construct's plating.
Kostadis Roussos: Grigam radiated a burst of holy light that seared two horrors within reach, while Daz hurled volleys of magical fire and force into the fray. Thorin struck with Dombringer, imposing disadvantage in one horror's next attack, with a sapping blow before cutting it down entirely. One by one, the constructs collapsed into heats of rust and broken metal. When the last one fell, the party stood in the wreckage of the sanctum, breathing hard and deeply unsettled.
Kostadis Roussos: Because the horrors had been mindless, incapable of thought or speech, and yet somehow had known exactly who was holding a key that no spelling candidate keep should have been able to detect. The session ended there, with the party out of time, and the mystery of the assassin's Law Ledge left open.
Kostadis Roussos: What the summary did not capture is that you suspected the one person you knew had… who had seen the drop of the key from Gregam to Daz was, Fembrus.
Ben Pfaff: from Daz 2?
Kostadis Roussos: Greg, you had, you, you had… originally, Colin had given you the key.
Daz: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Then, you had given Daz the key.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, I… I forgot that part, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, as you… yeah, that happened while you were out.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, when you went to… when you went to give your talk, you handed the key to Daz.
Kostadis Roussos: said… I don't remember what I… I don't remember what I came with, but since you weren't going to be around, I needed to hand it to somebody who was going to be around. So Daz had the key. That… Daz had the key. But Fembris, apparently, was still around when you… when you handed the key, and he noticed.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so, so, alright, so there's 3 dead things. Daryl is, of course, like, banging at the door. LET US OUT! LET US OUT! Then he notices the door is open, and is thinking.
Kostadis Roussos: he's about to… he's about to try to flee, right? The door's open because the creature smashed through it.
Kostadis Roussos: And Daz, he's… but just as he's about to run, he realizes that the only four people who seem to not want it dead are in this room, and so he looks at the four of you…
Kostadis Roussos: And asks, what do we do next, gentlemen?
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Ben Pfaff: So… We, we now suspect Ephembris?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so here's what you know. You know that Alcist killed Genusi.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? You know, but can't prove that Brookworm covered it up.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. You know that Alley Ivan Moore was involved.
Kostadis Roussos: But you can't prove that.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And you also know that a bunch of automaton came through the windows and the door to seize a key that appears to not be magical.
Kostadis Roussos: And you haven't avowed sitting here.
Daz: Hmm.
Joe Beda: I'm still… I'm having a hard time remembering who's who.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so,
Joe Beda: Did you produce a dock like before, or…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, the doc, like, before, has everything… yes, it does have… I didn't produce… I didn't update it, unfortunately. It's okay, it's okay.
Joe Beda: Okay, but it does have, like, okay, we can see who's who, because, sorry, I'm trying to, like… it's been a while. Come on, dude!
Kostadis Roussos: And I'm the type of person.
Joe Beda: I read a book, and I'm like, I read a name.
Joe Beda: And then, over time, I'm like, oh yeah, that dude. And then I forget the name, and I'll read the whole book.
Joe Beda: And you'll ask me later, like, oh, what was the name of that character that did X, Y, and Z? And I'm like, I have no fucking clue, right? So, like…
Kostadis Roussos: No, dude, don't feel bad, I mean, it's like, it's…
Joe Beda: No, it's funny, because I'm like, everybody's like, oh, you remember so-and-so from this? I'm like, nope, nope, nope. You mean the dude that did blah blah blah? I'm like, yeah, I remember that dude.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on. Let me just… I'll get you the last summary.
Joe Beda: So we think that, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Right, the most important thing, though, is that in the middle of Candlekeep, which is supposed to be one of the most fortified places in the known
Kostadis Roussos: In the known world.
Kostadis Roussos: you just got attacked by three Helmed Aurors, who are after a key. A key that, you know, is supposedly the key for the High Tower, which supposedly contains all sorts of magical artifacts of undoubted evil and good.
Ben Pfaff: Was there something about how you actually need multiple keys, or am I just imagining that?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, no, so there were… yeah, so the other… there were two keys, right? You know that Callan had one key, and you know that Janusi had the other.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: But you also know that Janusi's key was missing from his throat.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Right, the locket… the locket was missing.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You do know that between the time he was murdered
Kostadis Roussos: And sometime later, two people visited his room.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: You know that…
Kostadis Roussos: And so… and you know that Bookworm visited his room, and you know that she knew about the key. And you also knew that Alcarist didn't want the key. He wanted Janussi dead.
Joe Beda: Alright, so our theory here, then, is that Fembra's reported the sort of transfer of the key to Bookworm, and Bookworm's trying to recover it because it might give them some sort of advantage in terms of being elected to be the Grand Poobah?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's one theory.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Joe Beda: I think we lean on Fembris.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I'm fabulous.
Joe Beda: What do you guys think?
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Ben Pfaff: Best I've got, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, let me just do something here.
Joe Beda: Because I'm not sure that Fembrus is, like, a ringleader.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I just, just dropped the, murder investigation notes into the, Alright, infinity… alright.
Ben Pfaff: Oh yeah, looking at the notes would help a lot, got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, there's…
Joe Beda: Okay, so part 5… okay.
Daz: What do I like this?
Kostadis Roussos: Why can I keep doing some more of this going forward?
Kostadis Roussos: They're actually quite easy to produce.
Kostadis Roussos: The very last stands.
Daz: Oh yeah, I have the third door apartment, or third-story apartment landing.
Daz: We haven't checked that out yet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you did, you did check it out. That's where you found the note, the note that Janusi thought, that Cowan Strong branches
Kostadis Roussos: Thesis was all HUI.
Daz: Oh, that's right, that's right. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You found out.
Daz: I was in the wrong part.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, so Cowan Strong Branch. Yeah, so what you also discovered is that everybody loved Genusi.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, literally everybody.
Kostadis Roussos: Even though he was about to fire them all.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, nobody wasn't gonna be here.
Joe Beda: The fact that they were not a fan.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and no, in fact, they're all talking about how sad and tragic his death is.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, Ben, you weren't there for this, but Callum Strongbranch was confronted with the opportunity of putting a criminal in prison, or having his academic theories of crime being validated, chose, of course.
Kostadis Roussos: the obvious.
Kostadis Roussos: Easy choice.
Ben Pfaff: Easy choice.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, you know… A research program that's validated? That's priceless.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: Nobody's willing to give up their legacy like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: And when the alternative is just going to prison.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Okay, so while you're… okay, well, tell me when you guys are done reading so I can…
Ben Pfaff: So, there's a whole bunch of directions we could go here, from the list of what's still open.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: But there's one important detail that kind of is new… is scratching at you.
Kostadis Roussos: You detected magic on this key a while ago, and it came out empty. Supposedly, this is some magical key.
Ben Pfaff: You mean we did… we tried Detect Magic, and it didn't come out as magical?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: Makes me wonder if it's actually the right key.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and just as you say that, you do remember what, callan set.
Kostadis Roussos: Which was… I think… ERG.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. All right. Just as you're think… just as that, just as you say that, Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: They just said, you remember what he told you, Gregam?
Kostadis Roussos: When he gave it to you. I have given it now to someone who is not me.
Ben Pfaff: Someone who is not me.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, that's a weird phrasing,
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Ben Pfaff: And I… I guess it could be sort of a hot potato kind of thing, you know, bad things are coming to the… whoever is holding the key when something happens.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so what you do know is that the key has the… that somebody has a stone.
Kostadis Roussos: That could summon the key off of a dead body.
Kostadis Roussos: You're also… he also would be worried that somebody would kill him and steal the key.
Ben Pfaff: There's a lot that doesn't add up.
Ben Pfaff: Right. Like, why… it's possible that it is the key, but… we didn't…
Kostadis Roussos: You have Daryl, you could ask him whether it's the key.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, yeah, I show it to Daryl and say, you know, does this look like the key? Anything look odd about it?
Ben Pfaff: The key to the tower?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do tell him that… well, he goes, oh, yes, well, that definitely… I mean, do you tell him that it wasn't magical, or do you just show him the key?
Ben Pfaff: Well, I start out by saying, does this look like the right key?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at it, pensively says, well, I'm not a locksmith, so I couldn't tell you for sure.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so, but I was given to understand that these keys were supposed to be magical, and, you know, we tried.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yes, absolutely, they're, they're…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, they're completely magical. They're the two keys that are necessary to open the Hightower. They're not some lowly, cheap-ass keys that you acquire at a locksmith. Why?
Ben Pfaff: But this key is not magical. Go ahead and examine it, try to detect magic on it. We did not succeed.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at it, he looks at it, he pulls out his old trusty scroll of Detect Magic.
Kostadis Roussos: Because, you know, if your candle keeps sage, you have one of those in your pocket.
Kostadis Roussos: At all time.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? He starts reading the scroll, and, you know, your sword starts to… your armor starts to blink, bookworm is even brighter than usual.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, is this how, Detect Magic works? Everything goes…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so it starts to glow, right? Like any… but the key, the key is stubbornly not glowing.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, it's possible someone put a charm of undetectable magic on it, but…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's, he's, like, going, this, this is not the key.
Kostadis Roussos: This. Is. Not.
Kostadis Roussos: The key!
Kostadis Roussos: Benjamin?
Daz: It's just as that happened?
Kostadis Roussos: All of a sudden, you hear a… a watcher's bell starts tolling wrong.
Kostadis Roussos: Not the hour, an alarm pattern. It's impersonal, institutional.
Kostadis Roussos: Institutional.
Kostadis Roussos: It's as if the keep itself is reacting to something.
Joe Beda: What does that mean?
Ben Pfaff: It needs to change the battery?
Kostadis Roussos: Who's today?
Joe Beda: It's happening randomly, like, about every 90 seconds.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you, you, someone, someone rushes in. Bookworm is dead!
Daz: Who? Bookworm?
Kostadis Roussos: Bukhorib is dead.
Daz: Huh.
Kostadis Roussos: One of the avowed goats.
Kostadis Roussos: He says, do you want to ask him anything, or like…
Daz: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I have this…
Daz: How did it happen?
Ben Pfaff: Who killed him?
Kostadis Roussos: her, first of all.
Ben Pfaff: Who killed her?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, well, she had her throat torn.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, it was torn apart.
Ben Pfaff: Does she still have her heart?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, her heart… yes, her heart was in perfectly fine condi- well…
Kostadis Roussos: it was not beating, but it was… I mean, there's, like, this awkward moment as this person in hysterics right now. He goes, this is Candlekeep! These crimes don't happen in Candlekeep!
Joe Beda: Well, reality disagrees.
Ben Pfaff: I feel like we've done a poor job of Of serving and protecting here.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to go check out what's happening, what's going on?
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Fembris, Fembris…
Joe Beda: Oh, and I gotta talk to a kid real quick.
Kostadis Roussos: Jordan.
Kostadis Roussos: Fembrus and Daryl, rush with… rush all the way to the… rush all the way to the,
Kostadis Roussos: You rush all the way to her office, and she is, like… I mean, it's a pretty gruesome mess.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's obvious whoever did this knew what he was doing, because she is an 18th level magic user.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, but not necessarily a very… one who's very suspicious.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, or confident, you know, the safety of her tower, right?
Ben Pfaff: I, I, I mean.
Ben Pfaff: She's an academic, they don't usually… they're usually.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, instead of Time Stop and Wish, he probably has some, like, find reference to missing paper 9th level spell.
Ben Pfaff: Well, yeah, create citation,
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, create citation.
Kostadis Roussos: Validate citation, right? That's what you probably…
Kostadis Roussos: Identify false citations, right? Her throat is torn. There must be a.
Ben Pfaff: A lot of blood.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You do see a half-finished note on her desk.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, like a handwritten note?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: I, I definitely want to, read it.
Kostadis Roussos: He is using the beast to dot dot dot, and, you know, dead.
Ben Pfaff: The Beast.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: I turn to, I don't know, Daryl, whoever is there, and ask if they know what the beast is.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl says, I have no idea what the beast is.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, roll an Arcana check.
Daz: Okay, Arcana Check, here it comes.
Daz: I got… if you're fucking kidding me.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you get a 1?
Kostadis Roussos: You got a 1.
Kostadis Roussos: We want to help him.
Ben Pfaff: I would be delighted, to…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's…
Daz: I got, with some help, I got a 26.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, alright, so…
Ben Pfaff: Much better.
Kostadis Roussos: That is much better. Your headaches feel off, as if the pressure of the wards that protect Candlekeep aren't quite right. Something seems broken.
Daz: Oh, like somebody's got… somebody hacked the firewall and opened another port.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: And they snuck in some, like, you know, animated armor to attack us through that thing, or, you know…
Daz: Mmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Joe Beda: Maybe, who knows?
Kostadis Roussos: Who knows?
Ben Pfaff: Feeling awfully sad here. People keep dying, and we haven't been able to do anything about it.
Daz: Yeah, we gotta figure this out. So, if people are dying, and something spent… can I… can I tell? Is there anything that I know how to do to figure out what's wrong with the protection?
Joe Beda: Let's just be clear, we were hired to solve one murder, this is really not ours to solve.
Daz: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me go.
Daz: negotiator.
Ben Pfaff: You don't think, solving this will lead us to the…
Joe Beda: I mean, they're probably related, just be clear, but, you know, I think, you know, now's the time to renegotiate our fees, but it's not clear who we renegotiate.
Kostadis Roussos: with…
Ben Pfaff: You're saying it could be.
Kostadis Roussos: Completely a coincidence. Callan might be the right person, Oren.
Joe Beda: Alright, let's not get distracted. We can negotiate after the fact.
Joe Beda: When we have no leverage.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Okay, so, so Fembris is kind of, like, in horror, like, he's, like, completely, paralyzed in fear. Daryl is, like, like, standing really next to Thorin, right? He wants to be as close to Donbringer as possible.
Joe Beda: I mean, I'm with him, but yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: It's kind of getting a little bit awkward for you. I don't know if it's getting awkward for you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so what would you like to do next? There's…
Kostadis Roussos: No, the key… you clearly do not have the right key. The only person who may know where the key is is Callen.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, was Bookworm wearing the key?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Daz: Second key, right?
Joe Beda: Well, no…
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Joe Beda: We thought we had a key, but it wasn't the key, and then the other key we thought was stolen out of the locket, and we don't know where it was, and then there's the gem. Do we have the gem?
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't have the gemliner.
Joe Beda: So, we got Bupkiss.
Ben Pfaff: like, I…
Kostadis Roussos: Well, no, but… But you know something important here, right?
Kostadis Roussos: You know that… The only person that went to… Janusi's room between midnight
Kostadis Roussos: But the first person to go Janusi's room was Bookworm.
Kostadis Roussos: And she cut out his heart.
Kostadis Roussos: And she knew about the key.
Joe Beda: So it's likely she had the key, and that was the reason why she was murdered.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, which would be consistent with the attempt to kill Daz.
Joe Beda: Yeah, with the, with the attack of the… Alright, so these, these, what are they, Helmed horrors or whatever that attacked us?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Would they kill by tearing somebody's throat out, or was it sort of a different type of enemy that would do that?
Kostadis Roussos: This is more of a,
Kostadis Roussos: Claws, teeth… kind of…
Joe Beda: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Beast… beast.
Joe Beda: Gotcha.
Ben Pfaff: So these… these attacks seem…
Ben Pfaff: Quite different. Like, this is tearing out a throat, and the other one was more of a magical or surgical removal of a heart.
Ben Pfaff: Did I say something silly?
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so, okay, okay. So you… I just wanted to say something… yes, what did you say? Sorry, could you,
Ben Pfaff: So are the two… the styles of these murders different? Like.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yes, there's very different.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You do know, but as you're looking at that, Thorin remembers that Sylvara has an Abyssborne abysmal spawn.
Joe Beda: I do.
Joe Beda: Yes. I remember.
Kostadis Roussos: Apparently, yes, you do remember that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, actually, you don't remember that. Thorin remembers that. Daz remembers that.
Joe Beda: Oh, Daz remembers it, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz Sylvara… Sylvara has an abyssborne… abyssal spawn of a sun.
Kostadis Roussos: That she keeps him locked in a magical sanctuary to protect him.
Daz: Okay.
Joe Beda: Wait, wait, this is her son?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, she's a tiefling, she got pregnant, it was in the abyss, bad things happen.
Joe Beda: Things happen, okay, okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Joe Beda: I'm just saying, don't, like, you know…
Joe Beda: Don't… you know, I don't judge other cultural norms.
Kostadis Roussos: Did Bro get double tiefling? Yeah, so just to be clear, so Sylvara, you know, I mean, being in the Abyss for Sylvara, and she's… anyway, it's awkward, but yes, apparently she does have… so there is… there is,
Kostadis Roussos: And that apparently, her son had been not in his home for a while, and she'd been trying to get him back into it.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Daz: Interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and so you now connect that dot, that abyss will spawn, you know, you know, the madness of the abyss.
Kostadis Roussos: That might be a connection.
Joe Beda: Wait, what was the madness of the Abyss?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the madness that you guys have been dealing with, all the demon spawns.
Joe Beda: Okay, oh, okay.
Joe Beda: So, the idea there is then that maybe her son
Joe Beda: was not himself because of the whole, sort of, madness of the abyss, and then acted, but, like, what would be the motive behind that besides, like, demons be crazy?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, what you do know is that Alley Avonmore is really interested in collecting the keys, and the most useful thing to collect the keys is to open the Hightower, and the most useful thing to open the Hightower is to get some magical artifact of ineffable power.
Joe Beda: Okay, so that's the key to unlocking the gates to hell.
Ben Pfaff: Now, do they have, like, guards on this tower or anything, or just a key?
Kostadis Roussos: That's a great question. It seems like…
Kostadis Roussos: So, so, so Daryl explains, look, here's the deal. You have to understand.
Kostadis Roussos: We have got the finest defensive mechanisms in the realms.
Ben Pfaff: You rely on magical stuff, don't you? You don't have any actual guards.
Kostadis Roussos: We have excellent guards.
Kostadis Roussos: But, let me pause these. Our primary defense is a shield that protects anybody from teleporting in or out.
Daz: Oh.
Ben Pfaff: You know, we've.
Daz: Are we sure the teleport protection is working? Something feels off to me.
Kostadis Roussos: I, I… Do you have, like, a lot…
Ben Pfaff: arms, like, if somebody had teleported in… I mean, you told me they can't, but if someone had
Ben Pfaff: Would someone… would you find out?
Kostadis Roussos: And that's inconceivable!
Ben Pfaff: You know… Many of us have worked in some form of information security, and…
Ben Pfaff: Where, you know, inconceivable things happen multiple times a day, so… Could, could you, Chuck?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… He goes, well, it's very easy.
Kostadis Roussos: You… you can't light… you can't… fire doesn't work in Candlekeep. You must have noticed this.
Ben Pfaff: I haven't tried to light any fires.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, try the light one.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, I try one of my basic spells.
Ben Pfaff: What do I have? Okay, thaumaturgy, fire play.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see what happens. Give me a second.
Kostadis Roussos: Instead of this is…
Ben Pfaff: I'm sorry, I didn't catch that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so,
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl says, well, so you try to light the fire, nothing happens, right? Your spell sort of erupts, but then as it falls on the… as you try to cause the fire on the piece of paper so that it's not just magical, it sort of evaporates instantaneously.
Daz: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Burning bush kind of situation, right?
Ben Pfaff: Huh, I wasn't expecting that.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so, but what does that have to do with getting in or out of the tower?
Kostadis Roussos: goes, it's the same… it's the same magical effect. It's protected in the high tower.
Daz: It's protected by the Hightower?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's in… he suddenly connects the dots in his head.
Kostadis Roussos: It's in the room.
Kostadis Roussos: That is protected by the two keys.
Joe Beda: Wait, what's in the room that's protected by the two keys?
Kostadis Roussos: the ward that protects Candlekeep from outsiders coming in.
Daz: Is in the room with the two keys.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so, just to the.
Joe Beda: I mean, how do we know if that ward is still valid, right? Is there some way for us to test it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I… he just told you, you can't start fires.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, so that's the same ward?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, it's a Save War. Save War.
Joe Beda: Okay, so the ward has not fallen yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: But… But, but there's… there's, there's a…
Kostadis Roussos: There's two keys, and they have the… whoever has the first key.
Joe Beda: Well, and we don't know where the second key is either, so it's like we're kind of, like, down, like, we're 0 for 2.
Kostadis Roussos: But you do know somebody who does know, who must know where the second key is.
Kostadis Roussos: Caleb?
Kostadis Roussos: Kalen had the original first key.
Kostadis Roussos: Kayla and Strongbench had one of the two keys.
Ben Pfaff: And still should.
Kostadis Roussos: Or maybe he gave it to somebody else.
Ben Pfaff: Really, they should just not… they shouldn't just.
Joe Beda: Alright, so let's.
Ben Pfaff: It's shut around all the time.
Joe Beda: Clearly…
Kostadis Roussos: that she…
Joe Beda: Go interview him, and or protect him, and or see if he's already dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I think that is a fantastic stratagem. Okay, the next question is where? Daz, why don't you roll an investigation?
Daz: Alright, investigation, here it comes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, you remember that…
Kostadis Roussos: He said, if I don't see you tomorrow, do not look for me at my post.
Kostadis Roussos: He's not in the gatehouse. You, turn to Fembris, I presume, or Daryl, and Daryl says the most likely place for him to be is in the Sea Warden's Tower, lost among the other Watchers.
Kostadis Roussos: Rather than in the gatehouse. Hanging out… he's probably hanging out with the troops, trying to… trying to rally them, and throw… having a beers and alcohol as he celebrates.
Ben Pfaff: There's troops here? I thought we were in some sort of, like, academic tower or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there's some.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: We have some. We are not completely defenseless.
Ben Pfaff: Well, you have plenty of magic, but I guess swords still have their place, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we have some swordsmen. It's always important to have one.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, do you want to head off to the Sea Warden's Tower?
Daz: Mmm.
Daz: Yeah, I think so. Like, that might be where the room that needs the two keys?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, no…
Ben Pfaff: I still have the fake key, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you have the fake key, so let me just remind you, let's help, let me just, bookworm had a key, it was stolen by some… by some sociopathic creature.
Ben Pfaff: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: You guys were attacked.
Joe Beda: Anybody that would tear out somebody's throat is sociopathic.
Joe Beda: They may be well-adjusted with good methods and claws. I'm just saying.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Joe Beda: Weird methods and claws. Okay, anyway, so yes. It's a murderous, murderous character, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, fair, fair.
Kostadis Roussos: It's hard for you to suspect that it's an isolated incident, given that somebody summoned.
Joe Beda: Clearly, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Summon… summon creatures to attack
Kostadis Roussos: to attack Daz to seize the key. So the last possible place for the key is owned… Kaelin may know where the last key is.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. So, off to the…
Ben Pfaff: Gordon's Tower.
Kostadis Roussos: Sea Warden's Tower.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he goes. Alright, so let me just show you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so… Let me just show you where you are on the map.
Kostadis Roussos: Later, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Joe Beda: It's fuzzy! Oh, there it comes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, it's a very high-resolution image, and you know, the GPU, and the whatnot, and the holy hooty-ha, and the…
Joe Beda: blah, blah, and…
Kostadis Roussos: And the technology, and the…
Joe Beda: I blame AI.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you blame me out?
Ben Pfaff: There it goes.
Kostadis Roussos: I always blame Annie.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so…
Ben Pfaff: I'm starting to believe that in this realm that we're playing in, magic is the equivalent of AI.
Kostadis Roussos: It is, actually.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, which number are we?
Kostadis Roussos: You're, you're, you guys are, in 10, which is the,
Kostadis Roussos: the Great Library… sorry, guys, sorry, the Great Library, or…
Ben Pfaff: -Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Apparently.
Ben Pfaff: That's where we're starting.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you're actually starting in the exaltations.
Kostadis Roussos: And so what happens is you need to run to the…
Joe Beda: Whoa, what happened there?
Ben Pfaff: We got stretched. That must be magic.
Joe Beda: That's fascinating, I love it. Okay. That means we're moving really fast.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you are.
Kostadis Roussos: You have to run to the sea wardens, which they didn't…
Kostadis Roussos: Which is annoying. That's okay. We'll just declare the Sea Wardens over here.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you have to run over here to the Sea Warden's area.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Where you discover that, Kalen is, looking very frantic. He goes… as he sees you arrive, he says, as you're heading towards him, he's heading towards you. He's kind of belting himself up.
Kostadis Roussos: Putting on his armor, rushing towards you, he goes, Gracup! Daz! I heard the bell! Is everything okay?
Ben Pfaff: No, Bookworm is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Booker in his head!
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: Does she have the key?
Daz: We did not, see the key.
Joe Beda: Wait, did we investigate Bookworm's site of death and see the body and all that?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Yes, you did.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, we do.
Kostadis Roussos: She did. She did. He goes…
Joe Beda: I can say with confidence that we couldn't find the key.
Ben Pfaff: But we did not find a key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he turns, he says.
Ben Pfaff: He is gone. He looks at you…
Kostadis Roussos: The key is gone.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… Well, that's fortunate. They only have one of the two keys.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? It was an accident, it had nothing to do with the keys, right? It was just a maddening attack by Silvara's son. I told her that that… I told Bookworm that that creature would be the death of us.
Kostadis Roussos: You tell them the fact that you got attacked to seize the key or not.
Daz: I think we tell him and see if… what his further reaction is.
Joe Beda: I mean, there were enough other witnesses, he'll find out. But also, I think we ought to defend, like, look, you know, there's a lot of, sort of, the, you know, case of the crazies going on because of the demons and all that, so I wouldn't jump to conclusions and blame the poor kid.
Joe Beda: But, you know… I don't know.
Joe Beda: How old is the kid? Like, 300 years old or something?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Joe Beda: Alright, what else?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Kalen looks at you, here's about how you were attacked by creatures. He goes.
Kostadis Roussos: You got Gtukas. Someone is definitely after the keys.
Kostadis Roussos: And he says…
Joe Beda: Does he literally say, get zooks?
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, sorry, he says it in…
Joe Beda: What is the, what is the… okay, yeah, I'm sorry, go ahead. So, okay, he, he…
Kostadis Roussos: You know, establishing something.
Joe Beda: Memorize.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, he establishes surprise, he goes.
Kostadis Roussos: This is an important, urgent matter. He looks at the four of you and says, You are adventurers.
Ben Pfaff: Aye, aye.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I hereby,
Kostadis Roussos: That's what we're just looking for. Command you!
Kostadis Roussos: Or rather, I hereby deputize you as watchers of Kettlekeep.
Daz: What does that mean? Does that give us any privileges and or…
Daz: Change our abilities to do the investigation.
Ben Pfaff: So far, we've done badly.
Daz: Does it come with a stipend?
Kostadis Roussos: A small honorarium. But this is not the void. He goes, it's truly an honorarium. I can't promise you you'll be… Why are we discussing honorariums with bookworm dead? Someone out to capture the monster, and the second key, at risk?
Kostadis Roussos: He then… He looks at you, he goes, Taldrick has the key.
Ben Pfaff: Caldra.
Kostadis Roussos: Todrick, he's the guy who you guys met at the Genusi's,
Kostadis Roussos: Graveyard, at Genusi's, room. He was the gun guarding the room from people coming in and out.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, I'm confused now about who thinks where all the keys are, because
Ben Pfaff: Don't people think that one of them was given to us?
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Callan… Callan was the one who gave you the fake key.
Daz: Okay.
Joe Beda: Wait, wait, so how did we get the key in the first place? I'm trying to remember.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Callan gave the key to Gregor.
Ben Pfaff: Right.
Daz: Right? And then he gave it to me, and then we realized that it's fake.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I had set you guys up.
Kostadis Roussos: To be a target.
Joe Beda: That pastored, but we could handle it.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so he'd set you guys up to be a target, that's what you've now figured out. But he also…
Joe Beda: So, Callan was the one who actually was supposed to keep the key, and he gave it to us, but he actually gave us a fake one, and he supposedly kept the original, but then he handed the original to his buddy, right, or his assistant.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
Joe Beda: What was the assistant's name?
Kostadis Roussos: Tadrick.
Joe Beda: Kadrick. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Whom you, whom you met at Janusi's,
Kostadis Roussos: Early in this adventure, he was the guy… he was the guy, guarding Janusi's… the murder scene.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Joe Beda: So why… okay, so if…
Joe Beda: I'm just trying to think, like.
Joe Beda: So, somebody sent the dudes after us to try and recover the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: And they had the information that could only, as far as we know, be given by the dude who was hanging out with us, right? Yes. And the dude that was hanging out with us was buddy-buddy with the woman who was murdered.
Joe Beda: She was murdered because she had the key. So that suggests that she was the one who sent the people after us to get the key.
Joe Beda: But, in reality, somebody else thought that she had the key.
Joe Beda: And she may or may not have had the key, or maybe she got the key someplace else. So I'm just wondering, like, like, the people who, like, who's… like, there was one key to be had, and there were two attacks.
Joe Beda: It probably won't.
Kostadis Roussos: True Kidish.
Joe Beda: What's that?
Kostadis Roussos: There's three… there are two keys to be had. One was on Bookworm, and the other is Callan's other key.
Joe Beda: Oh, I see, I see, I see, I see. So, like, maybe she sent… or, like, somebody…
Joe Beda: Sent baddies after both us, and then looking to have the keys, but, like.
Joe Beda: In our case, they were mistaken. In the case of Bookworm, they weren't.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Joe Beda: And so they have one of the keys from Bookworm, the other one, if they had succeeded against us, they thought they would have had both the keys, but they really wouldn't have because, Callan pulled an old switcheroo and didn't give us the key, gave us a FACO key.
Ben Pfaff: Did… but we just…
Joe Beda: So he could have done something to, like, imbue some magic on that key so that it glowed with the tech magic, because the tech magic doesn't tell you what the magic is, it's just there's some magic there, and then it would have been a lot harder for us to figure this shit out, but okay.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, does Kellen know that we know that it was fake?
Kostadis Roussos: He doesn't… at this point in time, he doesn't care. He's basically telling you the real keys held by Tadrick.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay. He's basically admitting he gave us a fake.
Joe Beda: Kalen did it because he was being screwed over and passed over, and he was pissed that, like, he's, like, like, cold day in hell before I'll hub these interlopers type thing, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Joe Beda: Alright, so we should definitely go get the key from Tadrik, because we're probably better at holding the key than he is, because, like, you know, we got, like, swords and shit.
Joe Beda: We don't have a bowl cut haircut.
Joe Beda: What? Which is clearly…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Joe Beda: Disqualifying for all the.
Daz: That's not required, right, for this new role we're in?
Joe Beda: I don't know, I'm just… I'm reading the notes, and it just says, short human young bull cut is, you know, his role.
Joe Beda: Into the notes.
Joe Beda: His role is bowl cut.
Ben Pfaff: My job is beach.
Joe Beda: Exactly, his job is bulky, bulk cut.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: Alright, so…
Joe Beda: Do we know… okay, do we think it was the same people? It was probably the same person that actually went after both of us.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Which may mean that… what's-his-face, who's the dude that Fembris, who was hanging out with us?
Joe Beda: We definitely need to put the screws to Fembris and say, who do you report this to? Because it probably wasn't Bookworm, because Bookworm was murder, it was probably somebody else who then, like, came after Bookworm and us at the same time.
Kostadis Roussos: And he pauses at that point in time and admits that when he told Bookworm the information, Allie Ivan Moore was in the womb.
Joe Beda: Okay, so FEMBRA said that. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, after you put the screws on him.
Joe Beda: Okay, so now…
Joe Beda: Okay, so, number one, we say, hey, Fembrus, this whole idea that Tadrick has the other key.
Joe Beda: Don't fucking tell anybody, you asshole, right? Okay, so we tell them that.
Joe Beda: Loose lips, sink ships, dumbass.
Joe Beda: And then… And then, like, we definitely, like, I think we should probably get the key from Tadrick.
Joe Beda: And then go after… who was it? It was L.A?
Kostadis Roussos: Ally, Evan Moore.
Joe Beda: who… Clearly was part of the murder on the Oregon Express that helped kill everybody. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he's also made his…
Joe Beda: brains for the whole thing, right? So now this is a second piece of data against Ally that, like, hey, look, Ally had knowledge that nobody else had.
Joe Beda: you know, and it clearly, you know, wasn't Bookworm that, you know, started this whole thing, because, like, it was the same, you know, likely the same person trying to recover both keys, so that's the second piece of information against Allie. Okay.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, there's other theories you could come up with, but that seems like a good start, for sure.
Kostadis Roussos: so, so, so Callan is very impressed with you. It says, Well done! You have captured two of the pillars of the thricefold proof.
Joe Beda: You're making it sound harder than it is. I mean, why don't we just say 3 strikes, you're out?
Kostadis Roussos: pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: Three slashes, perhaps?
Joe Beda: Obviously you're not a baseball player.
Ben Pfaff: I'm kidding.
Kostadis Roussos: Three straight.
Daz: They're not a golfer.
Kostadis Roussos: No, dude!
Ben Pfaff: Three, three strikes, and you've got at least, what, like,
Ben Pfaff: You've got a lot of points in bowling.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: especially.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Ben Pfaff: Right in a row.
Joe Beda: Yeah, it's called a turkey.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: You, you know, you know, Paul, I don't.
Joe Beda: Did you know, I was at my high school this last weekend, and they pulled out the old yearbook, and I forgot that I was in the picture for the girls' bowling team. I was the girls' bowling team manager.
Ben Pfaff: Nice.
Joe Beda: Cause all my friends were on the girls' bowling team, and so, yeah, you know.
Ben Pfaff: That must have been nice.
Joe Beda: Yeah. Alright.
Ben Pfaff: I, on the other hand, was merely the yearbook editor, so…
Joe Beda: Oh, and the yearbook had several pages going, these pages blank because the students responsible did not follow through with their commitments. It was like.
Ben Pfaff: Really?
Joe Beda: It was amazing. Oh, God.
Ben Pfaff: God.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you serious?
Joe Beda: Oh, yeah!
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, like, I mean, it's one thing…
Joe Beda: Like, savage call-out, they should have named the students, because that would have been better, like, 30 years later.
Daz: Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: Wow.
Joe Beda: Savage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so they don't… I don't have this room here, but we'll just use… we'll just, declare. Alright, so what he tells you is you are… he's on… what is he… what does he say?
Kostadis Roussos: Where it's me. So, what?
Kostadis Roussos: Put this trigger.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, he goes, Tedrick, he's a loyal, and he's alone, and he does not know what he carries or what's coming for it. The echoing the hall, then the north galleries. I posted him away from the barracks on purpose. Run! He hands you a shortcut, a watcher's stare key to the barred north gallery door.
Kostadis Roussos: And it sort of cuts… it gives you a shortcut to the, to the, to the hall. Do you take it, or…
Joe Beda: And we say, sure, and I'm like, is this key for real this time, or are you just fucking with us again?
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses, he goes, on my honor!
Joe Beda: And the other one wasn't?
Ben Pfaff: He goes…
Joe Beda: Okay, wait, never mind, never mind, let's go, we run, let's grab the key. We can argue about this later.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, no, he goes… he's, like, running, he's trying to catch up with you, he's a little bit out of shape, a little bit on the older side as you're running, and he says.
Joe Beda: Little rotund.
Kostadis Roussos: And Randy says, just for the record, I figured that if they saw you with the key, it would be fake, the fake key would be safer. I couldn't trust you with the key of that portant's.
Joe Beda: Alright, yeah, it's like, have you seen our weapons? Like, Dawnbrenner here can take anybody off.
Kostadis Roussos: That's why he gave you the fake key, because he wanted.
Joe Beda: Alright, alright. We can argue about this later.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's trying really hard, and he just sort of, like, stops right here, like.
Joe Beda: Carry on!
Daz: Little out of breath.
Kostadis Roussos: Real. What?
Daz: He's a little out of breath.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, he's a little bit out of breath. Alright, so you arrive on… It's a dome rotunda.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, to arrive at the top of a domed rotunda, so let's just draw a circular room.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Joe Beda: Oh, are we gonna do the type of thing where we overhear somebody because there's reflecting sounds in the rotunda? Because have you ever been in one of the rotundas where you stand in the right place, and then there's another place, and you hear exactly the sound from the other place because it gets reflected on?
Kostadis Roussos: Would you like that? That would be fun.
Joe Beda: Awesome, but, like, okay, if you could write that in, that'd be cool.
Ben Pfaff: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, it's in.
Kostadis Roussos: It's officially it.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's tell you what the situation is.
Kostadis Roussos: So this is what,
Kostadis Roussos: This is what the rotunda looks like.
Joe Beda: Is it Rotumb, like, what's-his-face, that couldn't keep up with us as we were running?
Joe Beda: Callan?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, maybe.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, here, let me just… And just, don't interact.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see… I don't know.
Ben Pfaff: I like the idea of having something special on a rotunda, that sounds like fun.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Just trust me.
Kostadis Roussos: They need to just, get the right monster.
Kostadis Roussos: For this.
Joe Beda: Wait, did my sound stop working?
Daz: If everything just…
Ben Pfaff: I also can't hear Kostadis.
Daz: Oh, hold on, he must have lost his microphone.
Joe Beda: I just thought that something happened to me, and you guys were all talking with each other, and I'm like, well.
Daz: Oh, wow. I thought Kostadis was thinking about something and looking something up, so he was… he needed a minute.
Joe Beda: You can take a minute if he needs it, that's okay.
Daz: Yeah.
Daz: Nope, nope, nope, can't hear you.
Joe Beda: We all know, like, clearly we're not in a hurry to finish this game.
Daz: Nope.
Daz: We will call out to you when we can hear you.
Joe Beda: Yeah, you will get some sort of… Sign of jubilation.
Joe Beda: positive reinforcement.
Joe Beda: Virtual pats on the back.
Joe Beda: Sorry, I'm kind of exhausted. I was in Chicago last weekend with my, family.
Joe Beda: And my sister is an extrovert.
Joe Beda: And it's the type of person who just, like, plans everything, so, like, we had one day, and on Sunday, where we did an architectural boat tour of Chicago in the morning, which was amazing, by the way. If you ever get a chance to go, it was totally worth it.
Joe Beda: And then we went to a Cubs game, and then we went to the airport for our.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
Daz: We hear you now. Yeah, we hear you.
Ben Pfaff: Kostadis.
Kostadis Roussos: Yay! Alright.
Joe Beda: I didn't get home until, like, I don't know, 12.30, 1P… 1AM, like, Seattle time, so… and then I had a 7AM meeting this morning.
Kostadis Roussos: The creature has… while you guys were running around, the creature has jumped onto Tadrik, he's grappled him, and he's…
Kostadis Roussos: Torn, him… his tearing him apart.
Joe Beda: Alright, so we got a… Save him and his bowl cut. The bull cut may not survive.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Yes.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: So, if we have to prioritize the man or the bull cut.
Ben Pfaff: We're gonna have to make a choice.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on, let's, let me just, remove all turns. Okay, could you guys roll initiative?
Joe Beda: Well, it turns out the bowl cut actually gives some special powers.
Daz: Initiative… Whoa.
Daz: 7. That's not great.
Joe Beda: Oh, I got 19. I rolled a natural 20, what the fuck?
Joe Beda: Didn't I have something that, like, I had some sort of new thing that was, like.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Daz: Okay?
Kostadis Roussos: I was just testing my own.
Ben Pfaff: I'm here, I'm here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, so let me just getting… I'm getting on to Zaltier's, character sheet.
Joe Beda: Have we slept since the last action? Because I'm wondering…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Joe Beda: I'm still down to superiority, but I'm good. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: There has been no,
Joe Beda: No rest for the weary.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, West for the weary. Alright, Zaltiers, and we'll shiv.
Kostadis Roussos: Is a 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you guys already add your initiatives? Is that what I'm seeing?
Joe Beda: I, apparently I'm… I'm… I'm winning.
Daz: Mine is in there.
Daz: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Joe Beda: Alright, and then the, the NPCs and mobs need the Pit Fiend and Tadrick both need…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Tedric is, isn't capable of doing anything.
Joe Beda: So, kind of smooth.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: We'll cut.
Kostadis Roussos: Either… oops.
Joe Beda: I mean, the word moot just has bull-cut vibes about it, you know what I'm saying?
Kostadis Roussos: What'd you say?
Joe Beda: The word moot has vibe… has bowl-cut vibes about it. I don't know, somehow, it just… that makes sense to me.
Joe Beda: It doesn't have to make sense to anybody else.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, no, sorry, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, let's, let's move on the show here.
Kostadis Roussos: Same partnerships.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, when you see the creature, it's like this massive, powerful creature that looks not particularly friendly.
Kostadis Roussos: Kind of thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, 7, Scott. Should've moved 7.
Kostadis Roussos: CV.
Kostadis Roussos: posito.
Kostadis Roussos: 7.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Thorin, you're up.
Joe Beda: Alright. Well, I'm definitely gonna tank this shit.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna charge that, Adam?
Joe Beda: I mean, okay, so, number one, what do we know about this dude? Do we know anything?
Joe Beda: Could I do wasted in action.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know he's a demon, you know he's abyssal, he's a demon spawn.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, U probably has the same sets of resistances that all demon spawns have.
Joe Beda: So Dawnbringer's fire is not going to do any good against him, right? Because he's, you know, Hellspawn.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, she does… she doesn't have a… she's actually got, she… it actually might do, because she's, she doesn't act… it's not actually fire, it's radiant damage.
Joe Beda: Oh, that's right. Okay, so we'll do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, she's upset that you didn't notice. She's like…
Joe Beda: I'm sorry, I just… I was fooled for a second because you are a flaming sword, but you're right.
Kostadis Roussos: Flaming? Flaming?
Joe Beda: You are a Radiant Sword.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Joe Beda: Absolutely stunning. Beautiful.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl, Daryl sees it.
Joe Beda: Well, Daryl…
Kostadis Roussos: I still…
Joe Beda: To fund places, just to be clear.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, she goes…
Joe Beda: Let's cover this in therapy.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we're gonna have to cover this… we're gonna have to have a long therapy session about that.
Joe Beda: I know, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: So I'm, I, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: We feel the monsters kind of, like, going, I'm about to rip this creature's head and steal the artifact. Could we, like, get back to this?
Joe Beda: Alright,
Joe Beda: So we're doing the, like, whole Guardian thing, so that way, if the monster attacks anybody but me, I get an opportunity to attack, so that's why I'm closing here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: And then, my attack with Dawnbringer here.
Joe Beda: I don't think I have any excuse for advantage, so I'm just gonna attack here.
Joe Beda: You know, every time we play, it's a different display here.
Daz: I know, I agree with you.
Daz: They keep changing the interface.
Kostadis Roussos: They keep doing what?
Joe Beda: It's not undead, so I think we're talking… Total one-handed damage is 19… T- Wait, no.
Joe Beda: Because it's not undead.
Joe Beda: So it's gotta be 11 is the damage.
Kostadis Roussos: 11? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And then I'm gonna…
Joe Beda: pack again.
Joe Beda: Alright, and this time, the damage is 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: And then… Have I hurt this creature at all?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you have. Yes, you have.
Joe Beda: Are they feeling it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, they are.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Joe Beda: So, I'm gonna do… Let's see,
Joe Beda: I get one action surge per short rest, so I'm gonna do that.
Joe Beda: And I'm gonna hit him again.
Joe Beda: And this time, it's 8 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: So, yeah, that's… that's some damage there.
Joe Beda: And because of this… let's see…
Joe Beda: Okay, and then this is SAP.
Joe Beda: And so, what does SAP do again?
Joe Beda: They get disadvantaged on their next roll.
Joe Beda: And they can't hit anybody else but me.
Joe Beda: without… Me getting an opportunity attack.
Daz: Nice.
Joe Beda: What'd you say, Kostadis?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just… just wondering myself.
Kostadis Roussos: Nice. Okay, so, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Cool. Alright, Zalt here.
Daz: Whoa.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Results here.
Kostadis Roussos: Charges at him.
Kostadis Roussos: He's gonna go all in. Let's see if I can… let's see if I can do this. Alright.
Joe Beda: Oh wait, can I do it some more before I finish?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: I want to do a Hill Strike, which is an extra 1D6.
Kostadis Roussos: Pretty soon.
Joe Beda: So that's an extra 4 points.
Joe Beda: But it has to succeed on a strength saving throw DC-15, or have prone, so I might not get prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what is the DC truck?
Joe Beda: DC-15 strength.
Kostadis Roussos: He made it.
Joe Beda: Damn it. Okay, wait, let's see what else I can do. What else can I throw at him?
Kostadis Roussos: Keep doing that, because I'm, like, trying to figure out what I can do here.
Joe Beda: Alright, you do you.
Kostadis Roussos: I've been viewing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so first thing…
Joe Beda: Okay, so I can do…
Kostadis Roussos: get some system.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, so, is it worth trying to frighten him? I don't think so.
Joe Beda: He's not going to retreat.
Ben Pfaff: I don't think you can frighten a pit fiend.
Joe Beda: I could. Do you want to see me try?
Ben Pfaff: I'd love to see you try.
Joe Beda: Alright, we're doing… I'm gonna… Alright, where did that go? That was Menacing Attack on…
Joe Beda: Okay, so many syntax Strength, he has to beat a DC15 Wisdom saving throw, or be frightened.
Kostadis Roussos: You see 15 wisdom saving growth.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you know what the frightened effect has, right? It can't attack you, or he can't advance towards you or attack you, just keep that in mind.
Joe Beda: Right, which means I guarantee… I'm guaranteed to actually get a…
Kostadis Roussos: What was that?
Joe Beda: So, 15, and he rolled a 13.
Kostadis Roussos: 13. Yes, he rolled a 13.
Joe Beda: Okay, so he's now frightened towards me, which means that I'm gonna get the opportunity to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: By a few moves. Alright. Zaltir attacks. Okay. Zaltir, let's see what Zaltir. Okay, Zaltir will attack with his enhanced arm strike.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you all have a magical item? Okay, so, let's see. Where's the tech?
Joe Beda: Oh, wait, I also get an extra 1D8 on that one, give me a second here.
Joe Beda: So that's an extra 2 points of damage on them, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, did Zeltir's attack? Okay, so he takes 14… Zeltir, advances on him…
Kostadis Roussos: Send you back. Zaltir advances on him, and attacks him once for 14 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Tax again.
Kostadis Roussos: Or… 10 points of damage… And we'll use one of his key points to try to stun him.
Kostadis Roussos: And the creature is stunned.
Daz: Nice.
Joe Beda: Even better than Frightened.
Kostadis Roussos: That seems frightened, frightened and stunned.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… okay, so he's stunned until he is stunned, let me just make a note of that.
Kostadis Roussos: Eric, he is stunned, and it is Alfair… Caic means gonna burn.
Kostadis Roussos: So, very well.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so I'm going to then use my… let me just make sure that the stunning doesn't consume a bonus action.
Kostadis Roussos: Focus points?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and then I will expend another bonus point to attack him again.
Kostadis Roussos: Twice to attack him twice again while he was stunned.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, takes another 30 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Gargum, you're up.
Ben Pfaff: Hooray! So, we only have the one creature there, right? The, the pet fiend?
Joe Beda: His name, apparently, is Mosquito.
Ben Pfaff: Mosquito the Pit Fiend, okay. Well, so, I'm going to, move so that other people will be out of the blast, area, and then I'm really excited about this Javelin of Lightning, so I'm going to hurl it at the pit fiend,
Ben Pfaff: Attempting not to, not to hit any of the, you know, any of my compatriots here.
Ben Pfaff: So, that, missed. Fuck.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Daz, you're up.
Daz: Alright, I am… So I'm guessing a pit fiend is probably immune to, like, fire damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Okay, so I instead…
Daz: What about… that's also fire damage.
Daz: Hmm… I think I'm gonna go with a good old-fashioned… magic missile, since he's… Not doing great.
Daz: And hold on for next round if I need anything else. So here's my magic missile.
Daz: Quant.
Daz: So, that is… 4 times… what am I at now?
Kostadis Roussos: What'd you do?
Daz: Magic Missile.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Daz: At the first level, so, let's just say it was…
Kostadis Roussos: golden.
Daz: 3…
Kostadis Roussos: 12 points of damage, alright.
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Lauren.
Joe Beda: I get to attack again.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do, because Mosquito is, he is unconscious. He is stunned, thanks to Daz.
Joe Beda: What is… his name is… Moses Kodo? Mosquito. I just read that as Mosquito.
Ben Pfaff: He's… he's not just stunned, he's stunning.
Joe Beda: Alright, here we go.
Daz: Something's wrong with my character sheet.
Joe Beda: Alright, that's 11 points.
Kostadis Roussos: 11 points?
Joe Beda: Yeah, I'll do that again.
Joe Beda: Oh.
Joe Beda: Oh, I don't know… okay, so this is a critical…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh my god.
Joe Beda: I'm trying to figure out what I'll.
Kostadis Roussos: 30, you killed him, you killed him.
Joe Beda: Alright, so he dead?
Daz: girl.
Ben Pfaff: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: I expected this guy to be a lot tougher.
Kostadis Roussos: I wasn't expecting you guys to, like, win all of your initiatives, and for Bazalt here to knock him unconscious.
Joe Beda: I mean, even so, he would have gotten, like, one attack, and…
Kostadis Roussos: You only needed one.
Joe Beda: Really? And he could have killed the dude?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he only needed one.
Joe Beda: And we just totally, like, one-shot him.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, we ached him.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I just want to say, like, well done, like, you…
Joe Beda: So my going hard on him was worth it, okay, on the first round there.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, like, the going all out was the right strategy.
Ben Pfaff: Get at least another attack, wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, I mean, I have to say, well done. You, like, all sort of ganged up on him and knocked him out. But you still have a problem.
Kostadis Roussos: You have Ally Evanmore, who's got one of the two keys.
Joe Beda: I mean, okay, so the plan was that we were gonna, like.
Joe Beda: So the plan was that we were gonna kill him, but first he was gonna kill the dude.
Joe Beda: With the ball cut.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, to go to the Hightower. So you now know probably where he is. He's probably in the Hightower.
Joe Beda: Yeah, and so saving bolt cut doesn't really get us anything, except we're good people.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's Bolt cut?
Joe Beda: Oh, the dude that he had, he was attacking when we showed up.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, well, I mean, yeah, you got to keep one of the two keys.
Joe Beda: Right, but oh, if he had killed him, he would have actually disappeared with the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Oh, does he have some special ability to, like, just blink out of there once he sort of…
Kostadis Roussos: Disengage, and flying.
Joe Beda: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Although, with Zaltir and the Flying Potion, it was going to be kind of interesting.
Joe Beda: Alright, so it was kind of dicey whether he was gonna get away with the key, but you were pretty sure that bowl cut was gonna die.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. No, it was… no, if he killed him, he would kill him and then flee, and so my theory was he would flee, but you guys did a.
Joe Beda: I mean, like, not only did we keep them from fleeing, we saved bowl cut.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you saved… you saved Bold Cut. Tedrick is… I mean, Greg, are you gonna heal him, or are you gonna let him bleed out to death?
Ben Pfaff: I'm gonna heal him, of course.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Ben Pfaff: I have… I'm sure I have, appropriate to spell here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, true, how much…
Ben Pfaff: K1's okay?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yes, 1Q wounds is sufficient. He's… he's…
Ben Pfaff: Cool, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: His wounds heal, the blood stops, he grabs for the key, and he says, the creature, Mozikovo! He looks at him.
Kostadis Roussos: Sylvara's son?
Kostadis Roussos: What has happened here? Do you fill them in, or…
Joe Beda: I mean, he seems like he's a bit player in this drama, so I figure we might as well tell him what's going on.
Kostadis Roussos: He sits down in shock.
Kostadis Roussos: Is Calvin alive?
Joe Beda: I mean, when we left him, but he was breathing really hard because he was running, so who knows?
Joe Beda: extended there.
Daz: I gotta have a coronary, there's no guarantee.
Kostadis Roussos: You might have had a coronary. Alright, okay, so we will stop here. You all gain a level.
Ben Pfaff: That brings us to level… 9?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yes.
Joe Beda: Exciting.
Kostadis Roussos: We're now level 9.
Daz: The level, that's awesome.
Joe Beda: level without actually doing the work. Good job, Gabe.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Well, I mean, he did, you know.
Joe Beda: I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So Zalatir burned a couple of CAI points, and the creature is dead. You have one of the two keys, but as you well know.
Kostadis Roussos: Evil geniuses have more than one plan.
Ben Pfaff: What fun! So we have one real key and one fake key, and anybody who doesn't know that we have a fake key, we can fake them out with it somehow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yes.
Daz: And eventually, the person that has the real key will be like, how are these guys saying they have two keys?
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, that's a good idea. Interesting.
Daz: Might ferret him out.
Daz: Him or her.
Daz: Or they. Or it.
Ben Pfaff: Or Z?
Daz: There's zero.
Joe Beda: So, my wife does gender-affirming care.
Joe Beda: And she'll tell me stories.
Joe Beda: And I'm done with whatever pronouns, whatever, right? The whole it thing kind of creeps me out a little bit, but whatever, you do you.
Joe Beda: But there are some people who are, like, no pronouns.
Joe Beda: Which is just the most awkward thing, because that means that every time you refer to that person, you have to actually say something like that person, or use their name, or whatever. You can't use any pronoun when referring to.
Daz: I went over to Frank's house, and Frank made dinner, and Frank made the…
Joe Beda: I'm like, what the fuck, dude? Just like…
Daz: Dude, that's…
Joe Beda: Like, you're just… you're just fucking with people at that point, right?
Daz: said that Frank would share Frank's.
Joe Beda: I'm pretty woke, but at that point, you're just fucking with me, right?
Daz: So,
Ben Pfaff: We actually did that as almost like a word game in college, of trying to see how long you could talk about… I think it was…
Ben Pfaff: I think it was without using pronouns at all.
Ben Pfaff: A heck of a challenge.
Daz: Yeah.
Daz: Alright. Have you seen the caveman translator that saves tokens with your AI usage?
Joe Beda: I haven't yet, but I'm doing this whole thing where I'm, like… I'm gonna have a big blog post talking about how we have user experience and we have developer experience, but there's a new thing, agent experience, where it's, like, you optimize tools and systems to actually minimize context window bloat and all that, and so the caveman is a good example of that, yeah.
Daz: Just stripping all the A's and the B's and all of the stuff that's superfluous for, like, actually understanding context if you're a computer.
Joe Beda: No, but I'm building this thing where I'm building this tool, and I'm, like…
Joe Beda: and I'm having the agent sort of have a set of scenarios, and we're, like, looking at, like.
Joe Beda: you know, the percentage usage of context and how much it saves us to use one syntax versus another, and it's kind of crazy. It's kind of an interesting thing to optimize for.
Joe Beda: It's like, oh, making this change saves you 1% of your context. I'm like, alright.
Daz: Eventually, there's gonna be another breakthrough.
Joe Beda: Yeah. Kostadis, did we lose ya?
Joe Beda: Oh, your audio's… I'm silent again.
Joe Beda: Okay, you can… you have a week to figure this out, okay?
Daz: I think he can hear us, we just can't.
Joe Beda: No, I'm pretty sure he can hear us, but we can't hear you.
Daz: Now you're back.
Joe Beda: No, you're back, you're back.
Kostadis Roussos: Here, I'm back. Alright, so I'm just, I'm just trying to follow. So you guys, you guys, once again, twisted this adventure in new ways, and I'm gonna have to go do a whole bunch of preparation this week.
Joe Beda: Sorry.
Daz: No, no!
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, this is great, this is great, I mean, you know…
Joe Beda: You have a bunch of matrices to help you, so you're good.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I've, like, there's billions of GPUs burning cycles, helping me figure this out. I hope you guys are enjoying this, I'm enjoying this.
Joe Beda: Oh, we're having…
Ben Pfaff: Oh, it's fun.
Daz: It's a ton of fun.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, yeah, so just so you know, so the key, just so we all remember on the cliffhanger, you have the key, LA has the other key.
Kostadis Roussos: You probably know that he's in the Hightower, because he was going to be waiting there for Mozik Kodo to show up with the key.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Daz: So we show up in the Hightower, challenge, we get both keys, and then we own Candlekeep, right? That's how this works?
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly!
Joe Beda: Yeah, and then we can extract whatever boon we'd like, since we deferred negotiations.
Daz: Yeah.
Joe Beda: Until later.
Daz: Just saw one of the acolytes to go fetch a scroll.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. All right, okay, guys.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Daz: Alright, we'll see you guys later.